when Nick handed over to play for you uh
in 22 um
21, excuse me, how how important was it
to realize his power as the play college
but knowing you had just got handed in
mid-season or in the middle early in his
tenure? Yeah, I mean I think there was a
lot of trust uh between Nick and I um
you know obviously working together for
x amount of years at the Chargers um and
then going over there and you know the
way we see the game um and just going
going through that process um I think it
was good for both of us
>> with Tyler
you guys obviously
is there is the next
Yeah, I think so. I think he's only
going to progress, um, you know, in the
right direction. Uh, the way he works,
the way about he goes about his
business. Um, what he's able to do for
us last year as a rookie was pretty darn
impressive. Um, you know, so to add on
to that, you know, going through this
offseason, getting into training camp,
you know, finding new ways uh that we
can get on the football. Um, you know,
every offseason we go through and do
offseason studies. um look around the
league on how, you know, guys are
getting the ball position-wise, run
game, pass game, um and always trying to
involve, you know, in that in that
direction.
>> What opportunity do you think it
presents for Tyler and Josh? I know
Chris mentioned him yesterday, his
departure of Pitman, obviously targets
got to go somewhere.
>> Um what does it mean for those two guys
in particular?
>> Yeah, first off, you know, just a ton of
respect for Michael Pitman um and what
he did for this organization for so many
years, the toughness he brought. Um you
know, he's going to be missed. um you
know on this team and in this city um
you know I'm sure he'll do great things
for Pittsburgh um you know but with him
you know departing obviously Tyler Alec
you know Josh um you know getting more
targets for those guys um as we go
through this process and you know put it
all together um this spring and going
into training camp you know I'm excited
for those guys opportunity
>> can Josh play outside
>> yeah we'll look into that I think we're
going to look into that you know this
off season um and see where that goes
but I do believe he can Um, and so we'll
get those reps and OTAAS and training
camp and go from there.
>> What is, um, in year two with your your
quarterback, you want to try to like
build on things and and take that
offense to the next step. With the
injury, how much does that hamper that
if at all? I don't know.
>> Yeah, I think, you know, he's obviously
going to be in all the meetings, um,
locked in, ready to go mentally. And so,
I think there's going to be a lot of
conversations that take place this
spring. Um, then hopefully, you know,
he's ready to go in training camp. Um,
but I think year two in the system, um,
obviously a very cerebral guy Daniel is.
Um, so we'll have those conversations,
um, and constantly be evolving, you
know, offensively and, you know, there's
certain things that'll come up, you
know, conversations, little things,
little adjustments we can tweak to
routes and protection stuff that, you
know, he's really good at seeing. So,
I'm excited to have those conversations
with him, you know, this offseason and
we'll go from there.
>> Was there stuff do you do you feel like
was there stuff that you maybe left on
the table last year? I mean, as good as
you were to start the season, do you
think there's there's more on the bone
there?
>> Yeah, I think, you know, with anything,
um, especially at the quarterback spot
with Daniel, you know, going into year
two of the system, you know, before his
injury, obviously, he's playing elite
football and, uh, obviously we got to
get back to that. It's a new season. Um,
we got to restart that whole thing over
again. Um, but we're excited. We're
looking forward to that challenge, that
opportunity um of getting the work done.
>> Jim, when you're dealing with a
quarterback with that type of injury,
even when you're bringing it on board,
be it under dropping back or rolling
out, do you have to measure that type of
progress?
>> Yeah, I think that's a good question. I
think, you know, with his rehab process
that he's going through right now, um
he's attacking it the right way. Um he's
probably rehabbing right now, to be
honest. Um that's just the type of guy
he is. he's going to a relentless
worker. Um, and so we'll we'll go
through that process and, you know,
trust the trainers, trust the doctors,
trust his, you know, and as we ease him
back into this thing, uh, once he gets
healthy, um, you know, we'll see how
that all goes.
>> Shane, how do you, uh, I guess thread
the needle of, we start a two, a lot of
good things were there, new season, and
we got to start over.
>> Yeah, I think every year you got to
start over. I mean, regardless of the
results of what happened the year
before, every year is a new year.
everyone's zero and zero. Um, and that's
the exciting part about it. And, uh, a
lot of optimism, a lot of belief, uh, in
the guys we got there in that locker
room and our coaching staff. Um, and
going through that process and looking
forward to starting April 20th with the
guys, uh, getting back at it and, uh,
you know, going into training camping
this year.
>> Does knowing what it looks like with
Daniel though add some like, you know,
in Indianapolis that hasn't been the
same quarterback year over year a lot.
>> Yeah, for sure. I think so. I mean, um,
you know, we saw what it can be. Um, but
we got to do that, you know, start over
again and and do it consistently for 17
weeks, you know, and that's that's part
of this league and that's the challenge
every year you go and do it. Uh, is
trying to find ways to win, you know,
every game you're in, no matter what the
circumstances are.
>> Shane, I'm curious, you know, one of the
things that seems to be a trend in the
league are teams are doing more and more
joint practices, especially as the
preseason got shorted a few years ago.
As a coach, who I know you've done some
practice, what do you see as the biggest
benefit of that? Do you see them as even
more valuable in preseason games in some
regards?
>> Yeah, I I I enjoy joint practices to be
honest. I think it's it gives our, you
know, guys an opportunity to see some
new faces during training camp. Training
camp's long. Um, but also gives them a
chance to go against different schemes,
you know, offensively, defensively, and
special teams. Uh, and the competitive
nature brings out uh in those guys in a
controlled environment, you know, where
guys aren't getting tackled to the
ground. Um, you know, I think it brings
out the best in both teams when you have
those drone practice. Is there a a added
bonus to him being able to kind of
control the situations a little bit
more? You want to do specific red zone?
>> Yeah, absolutely. I think those are
great. You know, myself and the other
head coach, we'll have discussions on
how we want the practice to look like.
Um, but I think you try to do
everything. You try to get your first
and second down stuff in your third
down, your red zone, get a two-minute
drive in there. Um, whatever it may be,
and then special teams coordinators,
they'll talk about what they want to get
done. Um, so I think it benefits
everybody.
>> What do you think about um the the
offseason's kind of
had some changes to your division,
changes that are positive for those
teams probably. And it was already
competitive last season. Just how what
do you think what kind of season you
think is shaping up to be in the FC
South?
>> I mean, it's hard to say. I mean, every
year is different, you know what I mean?
Um,
>> well, you know, the coaching changes in
in Tennessee that that staff is really
good.
>> Yeah, I think so, too. I I agree.
>> Got an offensive line going.
>> Yeah. Yeah, there's no doubt. I mean,
obviously, our division um has been
pretty good the last two years, and I
think it will be good again. Um, and I
think, you know, there's so much parody
in this league. I mean, you look around
the league and the different divisions.
Some divisions might be down and then
two years later, you know, they're one
of the top divisions in the league. It's
just how the league works and how they
set it up. And like I said, the parody
and how the draft works and free agency
and it could flip in a hurry for a lot
of teams. So, um, that's what's exciting
about our teams have built on what this
offense looked like last season. Now,
with Daniel, how does like that
chemistry you have with him and him kind
of pushing, hey, if they do this, let's
do that. How does that help you and him
kind of attack how defenses will morph
to
>> Yeah, I think those conversations are
huge throughout the week. You know what
I mean? Uh when we're watching tape
going against opponents, um you know,
how to attack a coverage, uh little
nuances like I said earlier, you know,
we could put, you know, change a route
here and there at the line of scrimmage
or get to a run play, change of
protection, um off certain looks that
come up, you know, because you can't
give four play calls in the huddle.
Sometimes we give two or three, but he
can always get to what he needs to get
to uh given the situation and the right
look. And so, you know, I'm looking
forward to those conversations going
into year two of them.
>> When uh when you looked at the running
game and and some of the struggles down
the stretch, was there anything that
stuck out?
>> Yeah, I think that's a good question.
Um, obviously, we're always trying to
create explosive, you know,
[clears throat] runs, you know, in the
run game. Um, and, you know, we weren't
able to do those consistently as we did
early in the season. Um, and I think,
you know, you know, we got to do a good
job, myself, our coaching staff, um,
being multiple in the run game. Um, but
also doing a great job of scheming up,
uh, certain things, you know, for JT,
uh, to hit those home runs. And, uh,
that's got to be, you know,
consistently. I know you're not going to
hit the home run every time, but, you
know, if you can get four or five yards
a carry, um, you're going to constantly
be moving.
>> How would you evaluate edge rushing? Um,
obviously Quitty Pay moved up, we
brought in Michael Clemens, Ryan Key,
and lot to another year.
>> Yeah, I'm excited uh for the guys that
we just signed like you said. Um,
Clemens and Key. Um, you know, Quiddy
did a lot of good things for us at his
time here. So, you know, wish him all
the best at the Raiders. Um, but I'm
looking forward to those guys stepping
in. Um, building that chemistry with
those guys and lose defense. Um, getting
to know those guys. I think that's a big
part of it, learning the scheme. Um, but
going against Key when he was in
Tennessee, um, you know, I thought he
was a hell football player and Clemens
is another guy, uh, that plays with
great energy. Uh, looking forward, you
know, to what he can bring to our
football team and and building that.
>> It feels like we It feels like we barely
talked about Sauce last year because,
you know, he was in and out, but I mean,
this is a two-time allp pro guy. What
did you see last year that he can build
on and that you could you guys can
exploit in terms of his abilities this
year? Did you start to see some of it?
>> Yeah, for sure. Sure. I mean, the
coverage skills are elite and uh you
know, to get him back healthy uh going
into the offseason program, getting into
training camp, uh it'll be great for our
defense. You know, he's a lock down
corner. Um you know, obviously giving up
the picks to get him, you know, shows
what we think of him. Um and so we're
excited for his opportunity to get back
healthy and get ready.
>> What What makes him unique? Like there
are a lot of good
>> I think I think I think he's got a great
feel for the game. You know what I I
think some of those guys have a natural
awareness of spatial awareness and cut
splits and how guys are running certain
routes. Uh, you know, obviously had the
one obviously we, you know, we trade for
him and gets the pick six uh against
Atlanta where we got him, but you know,
he saw the split, he saw the quarterback
reading the quarterback's eyes, jumped
the route, like that's stuff that's come
from feel, film, study. Um, and so, you
know, that's impressive when you got
that. When you do have a guy like that
and you've got, you know, other a lot of
other backs, defensive backs back there,
like how much flexibility does that give
Lou to say like, "Okay, Sauces this side
of the field and now we can get, you
know, funky."
>> Yeah, for sure. I think, you know, you
can you can be multiple in what you do
on the back end, uh, when you got guys
like that. And I think, uh, Lou will do
a great job, um, you know, putting those
guys in position, you know, this off
season, however it holds out in the back
end with the other guys. Um, but looking
forward to, you know, those guys coming
together uh and competing.
>> L talked about wanting to play manto
man. Obviously, there's stuff you can do
against man just like there is against
other coverages, but is if you can
really play manto man, you know, if you
can line up both corners and go manto
man, is that more difficult on offense,
you think, than
>> I mean the windows are going to be
tighter. I do know that. Um, obviously
when you, you know, when you play zone,
there's some zones that can be hit, you
know, with passes and stuff, but when
you do play man, obviously there's going
to be tighter window throws for those
guys. Um, but I think you do have to
have a balance there. And I think Lou
does a good job of mixing that stuff up
with those guys on the back end,
different shell coverages, different,
you know, zone pressures that he brings.
Um, but I think it all goes hand in hand
with the pass rush and the coverage. Um,
and so looking forward to, you know,
seeing it, you know, come to life, you
know, this training camp and this
season.
>> One other thing on looking. Is it like
harder to find
even, you know, today maybe than it was
like 15 years ago when you started out
just as college playing?
>> I don't know. Uh, you know, I think you
kind of, you know, you study that. Our
scouts do a great job. Um, obviously
when we're going through the draft
process and looking at those guys, uh,
you try to find those guys, you know,
especially like Wall-E had some ones in
critical situations when he was in
Minnesota. Um, you know, a game on the
line and making plays and, uh, it was
impressive to see and I'm excited to get
him back, by the way. um coming off the
injury, him and Hunter Waller. Um you
know, they were having really good
training camps for us before the
injuries. Um so it'll be fun to have
those guys back
>> when guys are coming off of a season
ending injury where they like those two,
they didn't get to play games. Um
how how do you find the confidence level
just that they're going to be able to
pick up where they left off?
>> Yeah, I think it's the way they've been
working. Uh both those guys even this
off seasonason have been in there
rehabbing every day. They're in that
office, you know, for 6 hours a day.
just their mindset, their demeanor,
talking to them. I know they're excited
to get back at it and uh like I said, to
see the glimpses and the flashes that
they had before the injuries in training
camp uh last year. Um excited to get
those guys back and like I said, they're
they're re
>> is Hunter a possibility to step into
Nick's spot.
>> Yeah, I think so. I mean, those guys are
all going to compete um you know, on the
back end and we'll see where it goes.
>> With Anthony, we talked to Chris
yesterday and he mentioned that trade
request, but they're not ruling out that
he could be a part of the team. So, have
you checked in with them? And where does
that stand?
>> Yeah, we'll we'll see where all that all
goes. Uh this off season, obviously we
pressed the trade and uh you know, we'll
see how it plays out this offseason.
>> What how will you handle that with OTAAS
coming up? I mean, like does he just
stay home or like have you had that
conversation yet or?
>> I haven't had that conversation with
them. Um so, like I said, we'll see how
it plays out and you know, we'll let
Chris and his staff handle those
conversations.
>> One other thing on what I was one other
thing on sauce. um like a down year,
which I don't know that he even had, but
like a a year that was maybe not at the
same level he was like rookie year two
uh is is totally different for him than
maybe like another player. But that
being said, he does seem to like be
motivated to like prove I'm like I'm
still that guy. Have you got have you
heard any of that from him? We have
heard a little bit of that.
>> I mean, you see it out there down and I
think it's just kind of like I don't He
got hurt like you know what I mean? So
>> I don't mean last year. I mean I mean
like at the end in New York like you
know his first two years were so good
and then I'm not saying he was forgotten
about but it was just kind of like oh
yeah Gardner and then they trade him
right so like
>> I think he feels like I mean you guys
can back me if I'm wrong here but or
tell me if I'm wrong but it seems like
he he's got like a little chip on his
shoulder. I don't know. Do you have any
sense?
>> I think I think everyone's mottoed every
year to go prove their worth and uh you
know we're excited to get him back on
the field this year with us. Um, like I
said, I watching him when he was in New
York, obviously in elite corner, and we
got one and now he's on our team. So,
looking forward to that, you know,
coming up this year
>> with OTAAS. Riley will have a pretty big
opportunity. What kind of development
can he get out of getting those reps?
>> Yeah, excited, you know, for Riley. Um,
you know, obviously he'll get a lot of
reps in OTAAS and, uh, you know, looking
forward to that development to take that
next step in year two. Um, you know, did
some really good things for us. You
know, he stepped in the Jacksonville
game for Daniel in the last game against
Houston. did some really good things in
that game. Um so to take that next step
going into year two um you know he's a
relentless worker grinder um that works
at it loves the game. Um so you know
excited for him to get those reps.
>> I mean like what kind of growth can
happen when you're getting those kind of
the base handst you're kind of you know
going through it but you're doing it
with the you know the one
>> Yeah. Um it's it's huge, you know, it's
huge for the development um at that
position with him and [clears throat]
uh you know, going into year two in the
system, understanding the system, why
we're doing what we're doing, uh certain
things we can attack from a coverage
standpoint. Um you know, you want to see
that accelerated vision in year two. Uh
you know, jump off the tape a little
more and uh you know, excited, you know,
for his opportunity. Chris kind of
referenced yesterday that that he's
threw the ball better like at the end of
the season maybe than than we I I would
agree that than we saw like in training
camp just I don't know he just seemed to
have a little more I want to say more
arm talent I don't know more velocity I
don't know what it was there anything
there did he develop as a thrower
>> yeah I think you're always developing um
as a thrower as a football player seeing
the game um taking strides uh week in
and week out you know through practice
his preparation um you know getting
those reps on the scout team like he did
all year uh was beneficial for him to go
against the one defense all year and
then when he did have his opportunity to
go out there and play you know he did
some really good things
>> Shane uh going into the two Jay games
last year you had your quarterback
issues
>> which games I'm sorry
>> two Jacksonville games
>> oh yeah
>> what what were the challenges that their
defense presented with their scheme
>> yeah I think uh their D coordinator did
really [clears throat] good job you know
fixing up their scheme from a coverage
standpoint from a front standpoint from
a pressure standpoint Um, and so I
think, you know, that's always the chess
master game when you go against certain
people. Um, but a lot of respect for
what they did on defense, you know, when
we played against them this year.
>> When it comes to Carly, it seems like,
you know, she she does she's she's got
her hands in everything, but it seems
like one of the things that she does
really well is why you're doing what
you're doing,
>> asking those questions. is
how much do you appreciate just kind of
the the way she's trying to make sure
everything runs together?
>> Uh, I appreciate it a lot. I mean, I
think she really cares about, you know,
this organization, this team, these
players. Um, and so I think it's very
beneficial for everybody that she's
involved as much as he is, uh, cuz she
knows what's going on. And so those
conversations that myself and Kurt have,
you know, every week, you know, after
games and stuff and even the offseason,
um, I think they're very, very
beneficial.
>> Shane, when it comes to a first year
play caller, you think of your
experience with that. What are some of
the biggest keys to to navigating that?
>> Um, I think first off, you got to, you
know, find out what your players do
really well, um, you know, and then go
put them in position. And I think it's a
lot of film study in the offseason um to
take those talents that they have and
put them in position to go do those
things on the field. Um and then really
diving in on the tape big time when
you're going against your opponent. Um
the defensive coordinator, you know, as
you're calling plays against that, you
know, what are their tendencies? Do they
break their tendencies? And I think
having a feel for the game on when to
call certain things, I think is a big
part of it. I mean, you can be a robot
and go down a list of calls. Um or you
can have a feel of like, hey, I'm going
to call this play and be aggressive
here. You know, there's a time and a
place to do certain things. And uh I
think that's all, you know, a balancing
act. And obviously if the plays you call
work and you know, they work, it's like,
oh, it's a great play call. And
sometimes you might play call play and
it's not a great call, but the
quarterback makes it work and scrambles
and you're like, "Oh, great call." Well,
it wasn't a great call, but the guy made
it work. So, I think there's a lot that
goes into it. Um but, you know, Yeah.
Shane, how much do you think cuz Chris
hit on this a lot yesterday. Just
>> we believe in Daniel and like having
somebody believe in the quarterback,
believe in any player, the quarterback
in particular.
>> How much do you think that helps just
going into year two? Cuz not you didn't
believe in him last year, you signed
him, but there's just there's tangible
proof that it works.
>> Yeah, I think uh you know, it's huge.
Um, Daniel's a guy that works
tremendously hard and our players in
that locker room see that day in and day
out and I think it's everybody in that
locker room sees that and uh, so to get
a player like that back, you know, in
the fold at that position, you know, is
going to be beneficial for
>> How wonky did it get when it's him and
Philip Rivers in the same QB room
because I'd imagine those conversations
can get lengthy.
>> Oh, I'm sure. I mean, that day off on
Tuesday, they're right across from
Reggie's office and Reggie's like, man,
it was like Starbucks. They were just in
and out of there [laughter] all day,
just going in and out. And so I can only
imagine the conversations. I'd pop in
there a few times. Okay. Uh, you know,
on the off day, but they were studying
like crazy in there. And um, I'm sure
there were a lot of good conversations
that took place in those. How
>> do you think that was for to be able to
sit in a room with Phil for a month?
>> Yeah, I think it was beneficial for all
those guys. I mean to be around a future
Hall of Famer that comes in and just the
way he sees the game and the way he
talked about it and certain things that
he looks at, you know, on the defense
and tendencies and whatever it may be,
you know, that he sees that he's done
for a long time at a high level. I think
I think a lot of those guys took some of
those nuggets that he gave them, uh,
that they'll use in the future for sure.
>> Daniel is obviously very level-headed,
but at the same time, you know, there
have been some ups and downs, right? I
mean, he's heavily criticized New York.
he gets cut, you know, he has to restart
his find his path. Um, this kind of
gives him some, like we saying, some
conf instill some confidence in him from
you guys, gives him a new start. Does a
player need that sometimes after you've
gone through some things?
>> Yeah, I think you see it around the
league all the time. I think it happens
all the time. And, uh, you know, like I
said, we're excited to get him back in
the fold and what he was able to do
before the injury was impressive. So,
um, I know he's excited, you know, for
this season. Obviously, like I said,
he's attacking the rehab the right way.
Our players are excited for him. Um, so
yeah,
>> I know you can't see the Sorry. He's
been through a significant rehab one
time already. You think that helps him?
>> I think so. He's been through it. I
don't I think he's been through a lot. I
mean, he's been through so many
different things in his career so far
that like I don't think he's anything's
going to face him anymore. You know,
he's been heavily criticized in New
York. He's had an injury here. He had
another injury. So, I think he's been
through the fire pretty good. And I
think that'll make him stronger, you
know, in the long run. I know you can't
see the future, but with Riley, do you
feel confident in his ability to play
meaningful snaps if it comes to that?
>> Yeah, I mean, it's still early. It's
March, obviously going into year two, I
think, uh, it's going to be beneficial
for him this offseason into training
camp and see that growth and see that
development and we'll go from there.
>> From an offensive line standpoint,
obviously starting lineup, we kind of
know what that probably looks like,
>> but those those depth pieces, you know,
with Jaylen moving into the starting
lineup and you guys lose Danny.
>> Yeah.
identifying those, finding those.
>> Yeah, it'll be good. I mean, Freeland
will be back off the injury, getting
Tunuda back at the tackle spot. Um, you
know, Dalton Tucker right there at, you
know, in the guard spot. Um, so feel
good about those guys. Uh, you know,
taking the next step too in the
offseason program and going through
that. I think Tony does a phenomenal job
with all those guys. He coaches all
those guys the same, which is
impressive. You know what I mean? Some
coaches might just coach those certain
guys, the starters, but he coaches them
all the same. And Chris Watt does a hell
of a job, you know, helping them in that
room. So, I'm looking forward to all
those guys coming together and jelling.
And it's a tight-knit room. You guys
have heard me say that, but I think Tony
does a great job of keeping those guys,
you know, together.
>> When you've got a guy like Tony who's
had a couple of rookie offensive linemen
come in and maybe they didn't start
right away, but they could spot start
that kind of thing. Does it give you
confidence in if we take a guy in the
fourth or fifth,
>> he'll Antonio ready to go?
>> Yeah, I think it's, you know, draft and
develop. I mean, this is that's his
league sometime. You draft and develop.
That's what it is. And uh I think Tony
does that as good as anybody um that
I've been around. And so um I think
that's all part of it
>> with that. I mean you got one first
round pick, a third run pick, a third
round pick, fourth run pick, and a
fourth round pick starting. I I know you
probably don't look at it, it's like,
oh, it gives us like great ros
flexibility, but like when you think
about it that way, what Tony does pretty
impressive most lines that say are like
first round, first round, second round,
high press free agent. Yeah,
>> that that's pretty big for this.
>> I think it's huge and I think it's a
credit to Chris and his staff of finding
those guys in those, you know, mental
rounds. Um, I think that's all part of
the, you know, the evaluation process
when you're going through the draft
trying to find those certain guys and,
uh, Tony does a great job. I know Tony
watches 50 plus linemen at least, you
know what I mean? He's always in there
grinding and then when we do our draft
evaluations and reports and we're in
those meetings, you know, the scouts are
talking and Tony's talking and Tony's
like an encyclopedia. and he won't even
look down at his notes. He's got
everyone memorized and I'm like, man,
you're like Rainman in here. Um, but
it's it's impressive. It's impressive.
>> Also in the draft linebacker,
>> what's that?
>> How would you evaluate linebacker right
now? Obviously,
>> yeah, I mean, we're going through that
process right now in the offseason,
obviously getting a Gaither in the fold.
Um, you know, double A's, you know, back
in the fold. Um, obviously losing Zire,
you know, did tremendous work for us
here at the Colts for so many years. Um,
just a great ambassador for our football
team and off the field as well.
um you know got to know Zire really
well. Got a lot of respect for Zire and
wish him all the best in Green Bay. But
you know, looking forward to the
offseason challenge um at that position
and and going through the draft process
and uh all those different things with
the draft. Um sort of a random question,
but when you look at quarterbacks,
whether this year or any year,
>> yeah,
>> college football's changed so much like
guys are going to three different
schools sometimes
>> and you know, your scouts like to track
development, that kind of how how the
hell you even do that anymore.
How has transferring and and so forth
changed scouting quarterbacks? Has that
impacted it at all?
>> I don't know. It's still early in that
process. I think we'll have more data on
that um as the years go on. Um but it is
like the new norm. You know, back in the
day it used to be like why'd you
transfer, you know, I mean, you didn't
want to compete, you know? And now it's
just kind of like that's just kind of
what guys do. Obviously, guys are
getting paid and uh jumping from team to
team and trying to get their opportunity
to go play. Um,
>> how does it does it affect development?
You would think it must.
>> Yeah. I mean, yeah, you never know. I
mean, they might get in the right
situation if they do transfer, you know
what I mean? And it might help their
development, you know what I mean? Or
they might go from a situation that
wasn't great that goes to another
situation is not great and that could
hurt the development, but you never
know. They might get in the right
situation and the development, you know,
helps that way. So, I think part of it,
too, is a lot of guys, you know, you can
see, I mean, we'll see how it goes. Like
I said, the numbers and the data, guys
are going to stick around and play more
college football, you know, moving
forward just because they're getting
paid now. And, you know, it'll be
interesting. If you're not a first round
pick or, you know, high second round
pick and you're making x amount of
dollars, it's like, well, I might stick
around for another year cuz I'm making
pretty good money here and I'm having
fun with my my teammates. So, we'll see
how it all plays out.
>> Shane, I've got a quick one for you on
Rodney Thomas. I go over the Seahawks.
>> Okay. Yeah. Yeah.
>> What kind of player are they?
>> Uh, very smart, cerebral, um, did a lot
of good things, you know. Um he was the
multiple on the back end for us when he
played for us and he was our PP, you
know, a personal protector on punt. Um
but very smart guy, obviously a an Ivy
League guy. Um so, you know, excited for
his opportunity and see
>> Shane, when you and Chris sat down, were
you guys able to figure out why certain
teams play really well in December and
January and some don't? And I get
there's there's a lot of things that go
into that, but Chris has really harped
on not being able to finish the last
couple years. Yeah, I think that's that
you always you always want to play great
football, you know, in November and
December and and finish the right way.
And uh that's something that, you know,
we always want to do. Everyone's trying
to do that around the league. Um and I
think it's being consistent, you know,
for those four months, four and a half
months of football. And uh and it's
finding ways to win, you know, no matter
what. You know, some guys you look
around the league, um you know, some
teams are getting hot at that time, and
that's when you really want to get hot,
you know, is in those months, uh and
staying consistent. Um, you know, we you
got to look at everything. How you
practice, your practice schedule, what
you're doing there. Um, a lot of factors
that go into it and it's really just
finding ways to win, you know. Uh, you
guys have heard me say that, but that's
that's what it is that in those months
and those close games and this is a
one-sore league and you got to find ways
to do that consistently.
>> Change things up.
>> What's that?
>> Will you guys like look at changing
things up? Even going back to like
training camp.
>> Yeah, I think I think training camp was
really good for us last year. the way we
started, you know, we started fast last
year and, uh, I think there's a lot of
good benefits in what we did in training
camp and, you know, leaning on that to
start fast again. Uh, everyone wants to
start fast, but I think finishing strong
is the big thing. You know, it was a it
was a tale of two halves of our season
and we got to be consistent for 17 of
them.
>> Bit of a random one, but with JT,
obviously the volume last year was very
high, but also balled out. But do you
have to think about
>> workload and how do you evaluate behind
who's behind him?
>> Yeah, for sure. I think you, you know,
you want to keep JT fresh. Um, you know,
DJ Giddens, um, is a guy that's going
into year two that, you know, we're
looking forward to him, um, you know,
this off seasonason and the steps he's
going to make and the strikes he's going
to make. Um, you know, and going from
there, but, you know, JT's our bellcow
and when he's hot, he's hot and it's
sometimes it's hard to take him off the
field when he's running the way he's
running.
>> What type of player is Washington
getting in cross?
>> Uh, you know, he's a physical uh
physical player. Made a ton of tackles
for us. um you know, played down in the
box for us, did a good job of covering
tight ends, um but a relentless worker.
That's what they're getting. Uh he's a
guy that's in that, you know, weight
room at 6:00 a.m. every day working um
getting his mind, getting his body
right. Um you know, so excited for his
opportunity there
>> as somebody who's on the field like
basically every play that you guys ever
consider him like the green dot kind of
guy.
>> Um yeah, I mean there's always those
conversations, you know, um he played a
ton of football for us. Um you know,
like I said, and uh did a lot of good
things for us.
>> How versatile was he? um you know very
he played like I said he played in the
box uh for us a ton and but he can also
play on the back end too you know in the
deep middle um and so you know he'll
bring some good things to watch
>> Shane going into year four for you
obviously there's pressure every year
how how do you evaluate how does it feel
to want to deliver obviously having not
made playoff
>> yeah you want to deliver every year uh
you're in this business um and so um you
know I'm looking forward to that
challenge looking forward to that
opportunity going into year four with
this football team um a lot of good
things um you know ahead of us you know
that I believe that a lot of optimism um
and so I'm looking forward to that
challenge for sure you guys
>> what's that
>> Spencer's you know rehabing well um and
obviously getting Groovy back um will be
big for us and so we'll go through that
process in training camp let those guys
kick um and see where it goes
>> kind of more of a like a competition
>> yeah I yeah I would say so I mean
obviously with Spencer's injury you know
he's coming back from But looking
forward to both those guys. I mean,
they're both really good kickers. Um,
so, you know, looking forward to that.
>> Do you guys have joint practices
scheduled?
>> Yeah, we're working on some. They're not
solidified for sure yet, but we're
working on a few teams uh that we should
know here hopefully, you know, when the
preseason schedule comes out.
>> All right. All right.
Thanks